Guide to Major Figures in American Music
Major Figures in American Music
Oral History of American Music
Major Figures in American Music
1930 2023
1970 2023
OHV
Oral History of American Music
3544 Computer Files
2.42 terabytes
General
1703 interviews as of January 10, 2022. OHAM regularly conducts new interviews to add to this collection. This finding aid describes both digitized and born digital interview recordings in this collection. For digitized interviews, Oral History of American Music also holds the original recordings, on a variety of legacy audio and video formats.
Scope and Contents
Major Figures in American Music is the core unit of Oral History of American Music. It consists of over 1,7000 interviews with composers, performers, and other significant musicians. The first subjects were those most fragile in terms of age and health, such as Eubie Blake, Nadia Boulanger, Aaron Copland, Harry Partch, Charles Seeger, Claire Reis, and Virgil Thomson. Among other senior composers interviewed during the OHAM's first decade were John Cage, Lou Harrison, Ernst Krenek, Leo Ornstein, and William Schuman. As OHAM proceeded, composers actively involved in their careers were included and have been updated periodically. To name a few: John Adams, Anthony Braxton, David Del Tredici, Lukas Foss, David Lang, Steve Reich, and Julia Wolfe. OHAM's program also includes oral histories with emerging young talents, with the plan to track their careers as they unfold in the future. In addition to interviews with primary subjects, the core unit includes testimonies from secondary sources about George Gershwin, Henry Cowell, Harry Lawrence Freeman, Percy Grainger, and Arnold Schoenberg.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. The finding aid includes links to stream most interviews online via Oral History of American Music's (OHAM) AV access system, Aviary. Yale users can login to Aviary using their Yale University ID, to stream these interviews without restriction. Other users are able to request access to interviews directly through Aviary. For detailed access instructions, see OHAM's website. Please sumbit a Transcript Request to inquire about the availability of a transcript.
This finding aid also includes links to Table of Contents for many interviews.
Some interviews may not have been digitized or are otherwise not available to stream online. However, some of these interviews may have transcripts available (see above).
Some interviews may be restricted. Access to these restricted interviews may only be granted to a patron who has first obtained direct permission from the interviewee or their estate.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by surname of interviewee.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
mp3, mp4, mp3, mpg, mov and mts files.
Composers United States 20th Century Interviews; Jazz musicians; Avante-garde (Music) United States 20th Century; African American Composers; Women composers; Composers United States 21st century
- Abravanel, Maurice
  - Abravanel, Maurice, 1983 July 10; OHV 219 ww-xx; Lurtsema, Robert J.; Approximate Running Time: 41 mins
    Interview Location
    Boston, MA
    Abravanel, Maurice, 1903-1993
  - Abravanel, Maurice, 1984 July 8; OHV 219 yy-zz; Lurtsema, Robert J.; Approximate Running Time: 48 mins
  - Abravanel, Maurice, 1985 December 12; OHV 219 a-vv; Margol, Deborah; Approximate Running Time: 1065 mins; Transcript Page Count: 920 pages
    New York, NY
  - Abravanel, Maurice, 1986; OHV v219 iii; Nobis, Ricklen
    Univ. of Utah, Salt Lake City
  - Abravanel, Maurice, 1989 July 9; OHV 219 aaa-bbb; Lurtsema, Robert J.; Approximate Running Time: 59 mins
  - Abravanel, Maurice, 1990 July 8; OHV 219 ccc-ddd; Lurtsema, Robert J.; Approximate Running Time: 65 mins
  - Abravanel, Maurice, 1992 July 8; OHV 219 eee-fff; Lurtsema, Robert J.; Approximate Running Time: 68 mins
  - Abravanel, Maurice, 1993 July 11; OHV 219 ggg-hhh; Lurtsema, Robert J.; Approximate Running Time: 67 mins
- Abels, Michael
  - Abels, Michael, 2023 April 20; OHV 579 a; Edouard, Collin; 1 Computer File; 653 megabytes; Approximate running time: 65 mins
    Scope and Contents
    Presentation given for the Yale Glee Club in New Haven, CT
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    .wav file
    Abels, Michael, 1962-
  - Abels, Michael, 2023 April 21; OHV 579 b; Edouard, Collin; 1 Computer File; 18.5 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 152 mins
    Interview location
    New Haven, CT
  - Abels, Michael, 2023 April 21; OHV 579 c; Edouard, Collin; 1 Computer File; 902 megabytes; Approximate running time: 60 mins
    Interview conducted for a College Tea at Yale University in New Haven, CT
    .wav
- Adamo, Mark
  - Adamo, Mark, 2010 April 24; OHV 399 a-b; Platt, Russell, 1965-; Approximate Running Time: 120 mins; Transcript Page Count: 89 pages
    Adamo, Mark (1962)
- Adams, John
  - Adams, John, 1983; OHV 126 ee; Marshall, Ingram, 1942-
    San Francisco, CA
    Conditions Governing Access
    This audio recording of this interview is restricted. Access may be granted to a patron who has obtained direct permission from the interviewee or their estate.
    Adams, John, 1947-
  - Adams, John, 1983 May 23; OHV 126 a-d; Plush, Vincent, 1950-; Approximate Running Time: 184 mins; Transcript Page Count: 73 pages
  - Adams, John, 1987 December; OHV 126 o; Schaeffer, John, 1949-; Approximate Running Time: 32 mins
  - Adams, John, 1988 October 27; OHV 126 q; Dryer, Ruth; Approximate Running Time: 21 mins
  - Adams, John, 1988 February 9; OHV 126 p; Schaeffer, John, 1949-; Approximate Running Time: 18 mins
  - Adams, John, 1991 September 11; OHV v126
  - Adams, John, 1992 October 1; OHV 126 r-s; Wheen, Natalie; Approximate Running Time: 52 mins
    England
  - Adams, John, 1995 April 26; OHV 126 t; Swain, Donald C.; Approximate Running Time: 14 mins
    Louisville, KY
  - Adams, John, 1997 May 3; OHV 126 e-h; Perlis, Vivian; Transcript Page Count: 36 pages
  - Adams, John, 1999 August 12; OHV 126 i-k; Marshall, Ingram, 1942-; Approximate Running Time: 121 mins; Transcript Page Count: 44 pages
    Sierra Nevada Mountains, CA
  - Adams, John, 2002 September 25; OHV 126 u-v; Approximate Running Time: 73 mins
    Composition seminar presented at the Yale School of Music in New Haven, CT.
  - Adams, John, 2007 April 5; OHV 126 w-x; Approximate Running Time: 112 mins
    Composition seminar presented at the Yale School of Music in New Haven, CT
  - Adams, John, 2013 July 10; OHV 126 y-z; Marshall, Ingram, 1942-; Approximate Running Time: 100 mins
    Sierra City, CA
  - Adams, John, 2013 July 11; OHV 126 aa; Marshall, Ingram, 1942-; Approximate Running Time: 47 mins
  - Adams, John, 2014 October 16; OHV 126 bb-cc; Approximate Running Time: 61 mins
  - Adams, John, 2014 October 16; OHV 126 dd; Approximate Running Time: 65 mins
    Yale panel discussion, New Haven, CT
  - Adams, John, undated; OHV 126 m; Swen, Mark; Approximate Running Time: 34 mins
  - Adams, John, undated; OHV 126 n; Boschetty, Radek; Approximate Running Time: 12 mins
- Adams, John Luther
  - Adams, John Luther, 1989 January 27; OHV 422 f; Duffie, Bruce; Approximate Running Time: 43 mins
    Chicago, IL
    Adams, John Luther, 1953-
  - Adams, John Luther, 2012 April 16; OHV 422 a-e; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 217 mins
  - Adams, John Luther, 2016 August 4; OHV 422 g-l; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 169 mins
    This material is restricted. Access may be granted to a patron who has obtained direct permission from the interviewee or their estate.
- Adams, Samuel
  - Adams, Samuel, 2010 June 8; OHV 411 a-e; Valenti, Maura; Approximate Running Time: 168 mins
    Adams, Samuel Carl, 1985-
- Adler, Samuel
  - Adler, Samuel, 2001 February 14; OHV 315 a-b; Approximate Running Time: 98 mins
    Adler, Samuel, 1928-
  - Adler, Samuel, 2021 June 21; OHV 315 c; Bendian, Gregg; 1 Computer File; 1.81 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 122 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat. with interviewee in Perrysburg, OH and interviewer in Fair Lawn, NJ.
    .mp4 file
    As a preservation measure, original computer files may not be used. Digital access copies must be provided for use.
  - Adler, Samuel, 2021 June 28; OHV 315 d; Bendian, Gregg; 1 Computer File; 1.69 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 118 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee in Perrysburg, OH, and interviewer in Fair Lawn, NJ.
- Adolphe, Bruce
  - Adolphe, Bruce, 2015 July 24; OHV 483 a-g; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 165 mins
    Adolphe, Bruce
- Akiho, Andy
  - Akiho, Andy, 2011 October 8; OHV 412 a-b; Valenti, Maura; Approximate Running Time: 142 mins
    Princeton, NJ
    Akiho, Andy
  - Akiho, Andy, 2011 October 9; OHV 412 c; Valenti, Maura; Approximate Running Time: 142 mins
  - Akiho, Andy and Sandbox Percussion, 2023 February 3; OHV 412 d; Theofanidis, Christopher, 1967-; 1 Computer File; 524 megabytes; Approximate running time: 52 mins
    This interview presented as a composition seminar at the Yale School of Music in New Haven, CT with interviewer and ensemble members present, and Akiho on videochat.
    Akiho, Andy; Sandbox Percussion; Caccese, Victor; Rosenbaum, Ian David; Allen, Jonny, 1989-; Sweeney, Terry, (Percussionist)
- Akiyoshi, Toshiko
  - Akiyoshi, Toshiko, 2017 January 11; OHV 495 a-d; Bendian, Gregg; Approximate Running Time: 126 mins
    Akiyoshi, Toshiko, 1929-
- Albert, Stephen
  - Albert, Stephen, 1986 December 13; OHV 184 a-i; Grimes, Ev; Approximate Running Time: 254 mins; Transcript Page Count: 152 pages
    Newton, MA
    Emery, Stephen A. (Stephen Albert), 1841-1891
  - Albert, Stephen, 1990 December 9; OHV 184 j; Duffie, Bruce; Approximate Running Time: 74 mins
    Interviewer
    Interviewer, Chicago, IL; Interviewee, Newton, MA
- Alexander, Kathryn
  - Alexander, Kathryn, 2011 April 7; OHV 407 a; Approximate Running Time: 30 mins
    Alexander, Kathryn, 1955-
  - Alexander, Kathryn, 2011 December 1; OHV 407 b; Approximate Running Time: 28 mins
  - Alexander, Kathryn, 2013 October 31; OHV 407 c; Approximate Running Time: 24 mins
  - Alexander, Kathryn, 2015 April 16; OHV 407 d-g; Approximate Running Time: 18 mins
  - Alexander, Kathryn, 2016 April 29; OHV 407 h; Approximate Running Time: 14 mins
  - Alexander, Kathryn, 2016 November 10; OHV 407 i; Approximate Running Time: 53 mins
  - Alexander, Kathryn, 2017 November 22; OHV 407 j; Approximate Running Time: 20 mins
  - Alexander, Kathryn, 2020 February 20; OHV 407 k; Alexander, Kathryn, 1955-; 2 Computer Files; 256 megabytes; Approximate running time: 25 mins
    .wav files
  - Alexander, Kathryn, 2020 November 19; OHV 407 l-m; 2 Computer Files; 203 megabytes; Approximate running time: 24 mins
    .mp4 files
  - Alexander, Kathryn, 2021 December 2; OHV 407 n; 1 Computer File; 197 megabytes; Approximate running time: 20 mins
  - Alexander, Kathryn, 2022 November 3; OHV 407 o; 2 Computer Files; 222 megabytes; Approximate running time: 22mins
    Composition seminar presented at the Yale School of Music in New Haven, CT. Recording begins 1-2 minutes after the start of the presentation.
  - Alexander, Kathryn, 2024 February 8; OHV 407 p; 1 Computer File; 191 megabytes; Approximate running time: 19 mins
- Alexander, Monty
  - Alexander, Monty, 2019 July 11; OHV 531 a-e; Bendian, Gregg; Approximate Running Time: 172 mins
    Alexander, Monty
- Alles, Hal
  - Alles, Hal, 1978 June 14; OHV 211 a-b; Kretschmer, Joan Thomson; Approximate Running Time: 77 mins; Transcript Page Count: 38 pages
    Murray Hill, NJ
    Alles, Hal
- Amirkhanian, Charles
  - Amirkhanian, Charles, 1983 May 26; OHV 128 a-e; Plush, Vincent, 1950-; Approximate Running Time: 196 mins; Transcript Page Count: 92 pages
    El Cerrito, CA
    Amirkhanian, Charles
  - Amirkhanian, Charles, 2023 April 17; OHV 128 f-i; Van Cleve, Libby; 4 Computer Files; 3.28 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 222 mins
- Amram, David
  - Amram, David, 1967; OHV 6 k; Transcript Page Count: 5 pages
    Amram, David, 1930-
  - Amram, David, 1977 July 31; OHV 6 f; Approximate Running Time: 53 mins
  - Amram, David, 1978 June 18; OHV 6 a-b; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 175 mins; Transcript Page Count: 71 pages
  - Amram, David, 1978 June 28; OHV 6 c-d
  - Amram, David, 1984 April 22; OHV 6 e; Moore, Herbert
    Patterson, NY
  - Amram, David, 2002 February 13; OHV 6 g-j; Raymond, Jenny; Approximate Running Time: 177 mins; Transcript Page Count: 73 pages
- Anderson, Beth
  - Anderson, Beth, 1986 November 14; OHV 182 a-i; Grimes, Ev; Approximate Running Time: 243 mins; Transcript Page Count: 96 pages
    Anderson, Beth, 1950-
- Anderson, Laurie
  - Anderson, Laurie, 2018 December 11; OHV 522 a-c; Bendian, Gregg; Approximate Running Time: 78 mins
    Anderson, Laurie, 1947-
  - Anderson, Laurie, undated; OHV v41d; Perlis, Vivian
    Anderson, Laurie, 1947-; Cage, John, 1912-1992
- Andres, Timo
  - Andres, Timo, 2010 May 25; OHV 398 a-c; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 227 mins; Transcript Page Count: 110 pages
    Andres, Timothy
  - Andres, Timo, 2021 July 15; OHV 398 d-g; Van Cleve, Libby; 4 Computer Files; 3.70 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 251 mins
    Brooklyn, NY
    Other Finding Aids
- Andriessen, Louis
  - Andriessen, Louis, 1996 February 13; OHV 484 b-c
    Andriessen, Louis,, 1939-
  - Andriessen, Louis, 2015 October 8; OHV 484 a; Approximate Running Time: 60 mins
- Antoniou, Theodore
  - Antoniou, Theodore, 1986 October 22; OHV 183 a-e; Grimes, Ev; Approximate Running Time: 136 mins; Transcript Page Count: 45 and 54 pages
    Antoniou, Theodore, 1935-2018
- Appleton, Jon
  - Appleton, Jon, 1977 August 3; OHV 203 a-b; Kretschmer, Joan Thomson; Approximate Running Time: 163 mins; Transcript Page Count: 57 pages
    Norwich, VT, New York, NY
    Appleton, Jon, 1939-
  - Appleton, Jon, 1977 October 22; OHV 203 e-g; Kretschmer, Joan Thomson; Approximate Running Time: 105 mins
  - Appleton, Jon, 1978 April 6; OHV 203 c-d
- Argento, Dominick
  - Argento, Dominick, 1985 October 31; OHV 286 a; Bush, David Martin; Approximate Running Time: 25 mins
    Argento, Dominick
  - Argento, Dominick, 1986 June 6; OHV 286 b; Duffie, Bruce; Approximate Running Time: 47 mins
  - Argento, Dominick, 2008 May 25; OHV 286 c-d; Platt, Russell, 1965-; Approximate Running Time: 103 mins; Transcript Page Count: 72 pages
    Minneapolis, MN
- Armstrong, Louis
  - Armstrong, Louis, ca. 1950; OHV 598 a-b; Conover, Willis; 2 Audio Discs (CD) (Box 39002038328408, Item barcode 39002038328341, Item barcode 39002038328358)
    Interview conducted for Voice of America broadcast
    General
    Digitization of this recording is currently in process. Once digitized, it will be available for streaming.
    Armstrong, Louis, 1901-1971
  - Armstrong, Louis, ca. 1950; OHV 598 c-d; Conover, Willis; 2 Audio Discs (CD) (Box 39002038328408, Item barcode 39002038328366, Item barcode 39002038328374)
  - Armstrong, Louis, ca. 1950; OHV 598 e-f; Conover, Willis; 2 Audio Discs (CD) (Box 39002038328408, Item barcode 39002038328382, Item barcode 39002038328390)
- Ashley, Robert
  - Ashley, Robert, 1967 May 2; OHV 289 f-g; Jory, Margaret, 1937-1985 (Box 39002038324183, Item barcode 39002133913807)
    Ann Arbor, MI
    Ashley, Robert, 1930-2014
  - Ashley, Robert, 1998 May 26; OHV 289 a-e; Soltes, Eva; Approximate Running Time: 193 mins; Transcript Page Count: 54 pages
- Asia, Daniel
  - Asia, Daniel, 1995 November 7; OHV 361 j
    Asia, Daniel
  - Asia, Daniel, 2007 June 10; OHV 361 a-d; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 209 mins; Transcript Page Count: 121 pages
  - Asia, Daniel, 2007 November 8; OHV 361 e-g; Van Cleve, Libby; Approximate Running Time: 212 mins; Transcript Page Count: 126 pages
  - Asia, Daniel, 2011 November 2; OHV 361 h; Approximate Running Time: 82 mins
    Slifka Center Lecture, New Haven, CT
  - Asia, Daniel, 2011 November 3; OHV 361 i; Approximate Running Time: 83 mins
- Auric, Georges
  - Auric, Georges, 1978 June 11; OHV 314 a; Sherman, Robert; Approximate Running Time: 23 mins
    Auric, Georges, 1899-1983
- Austin, Larry
  - Austin, Larry, 1983 April 15; OHV 115 a-d; Plush, Vincent, 1950-; Approximate Running Time: 192 mins; Transcript Page Count: 78 pages
    Denton, TX
    Austin, Larry, 1930-
  - Austin, Larry, 1983 September 30; OHV 115 e-g; Plush, Vincent, 1950-; Approximate Running Time: 112 mins; Transcript Page Count: 78 pages
- Ausubel, Hillel
  - Ausubel, Hillel, undated; OHV MCD19; Hawkshaw, Susan, (Musicologist)
    Yale University, New Haven, CT
    Ausubel, Hillel
- Avakian, George
  - Avakian, George, 2007 November 28; OHV 382 a-c; Mattis, Olivia; Approximate Running Time: 411 mins; Transcript Page Count: 194 pages
    Riverdale, NY
    Avakian, George
- Avshalomov, Jacob
  - Avshalomov, Jacob, 2003 April 4; OHV 329 a-e; Hawkshaw, Susan, (Musicologist); Approximate Running Time: 187 mins; Transcript Page Count: 76 pages
    Columbia Univ. New York, NY
    Avshalomov, Jacob, 1919-2013
- Babbitt, Milton
  - Babbitt, Milton, 1979 November 6; OHV 233 sssss-ttttt; Olmstead, Andrea; Approximate Running Time: 83 mins
    Babbitt, Milton, 1916-2011
  - Babbitt, Milton, 1983 January 25; OHV 105 a-d; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 157 mins; Transcript Page Count: 85 pages
  - Babbitt, Milton, 1984 June 29; OHV 105 e-f; Grimes, Ev; Approximate Running Time: 64 mins; Transcript Page Count: 18 pages
  - Babbitt, Milton, 1985 November 28; OHV 105 o; Page, Tim, 1954-; Approximate Running Time: 57 mins
  - Babbitt, Milton, 1986 April 17; OHV 105 g-h; Page, Tim, 1954-; Approximate Running Time: 58 mins
    Tim Page
  - Babbitt, Milton, 1991 November 4; OHV 105 p; Approximate Running Time: 51 mins
    Harvard University
  - Babbitt, Milton, 2000 December 12; OHV 105 i-k; Marshall, Ingram, 1942-; Approximate Running Time: 122 mins; Transcript Page Count: 70 pages
  - Babbitt, Milton, 2001 April 5; OHV 105 l-n; Approximate Running Time: 101 mins
- Balch, Katherine
  - Balch, Katherine, 2022 April 28; OHV 561 a; 1 Computer File; 751 megabytes; Approximate running time: 74 mins
    Balch, Katherine
  - Balch, Katherine, 2022 October 6; OHV 561 b; 1 Computer File; 1.56 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 106 mins.
  - Balch, Katherine, 2023 October 26; OHV 561 c; 2 Computer Files; 375 megabytes; Approximate running time: 37 mins
- Barber, Samuel
  - Barber, Samuel, 1949 June 19; OHV 81 c; Fassett, James, 1904-1986; Approximate Running Time: 13 mins; Transcript Page Count: 10 pages
    Barber, Samuel, 1910-1981
  - Barber, Samuel, 1977 1979; OHV 81 d; Grimes, Ev; Approximate Running Time: 7 mins; Transcript Page Count: 4 pages
  - Barber, Samuel, 1978 September 30; OHV 81 a; Sherman, Robert; Approximate Running Time: 54 mins; Transcript Page Count: 19 pages
  - Barber, Samuel, 1982 January; OHV 81 b; Dickinson, Peter, 1934-
- Barlow, Howard
  - Barlow, Howard, 1951 March 1951 June; OHV 64 a-c; Hill, Frank Ernest, 1888-1969; Transcript Page Count: 220 pages
    Barlow, Howard, 1892-1972
- Barron, Kenny
  - Barron, Kenny, 2021 October 6; OHV 550 a; Bendian, Gregg; 1 Computer File; 624 megabytes; Approximate running time: 157 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee in Brooklyn, NY and interviewer in Fair Lawn, NJ.
    Barron, Kenny (1943-06-09-)
- Basie, Count
  - Basie, Count, 1979 July 5; OHV 260 a; Friedner, Carl; Transcript Page Count: 3 pages
    Stockholm, Sweden
    Basie, Count, 1904-1984
- Bayolo, Armando
  - Bayolo, Armando, 2023 October 19; OHV 585 a; 1 Computer File; 677 megabytes; Approximate running time: 67 mins
    Bayolo, Armando Jesús
- Beaser, Robert
  - Beaser, Robert, 1987 April 25; OHV 191 a-g; Grimes, Ev; Approximate Running Time: 185 mins; Transcript Page Count: 72 pages
    Beaser, Robert (1954-05-29-)
  - Beaser, Robert, 1998 October 6; OHV 191 h-k; Marshall, Ingram, 1942-; Approximate Running Time: 157 mins; Transcript Page Count: 68 pages
  - Beaser, Robert, 2001 March 1; OHV 191 l-m; Approximate Running Time: 82 mins
- Becker, Dan
  - Becker, Dan, 2004 April 2; OHV 339 e; Vees, Jack (1955-); Approximate Running Time: 139 mins
    Becker, Dan, 1960-
  - Becker, Dan, 2004 May 4; OHV 339 a-d; Van Cleve, Libby; Transcript Page Count: 110 pages
- Beeson, Jack
  - Beeson, Jack, circa 1967; OHV 300 y-z; Jory, Margaret, 1937-1985
    Beeson, Jack, 1921-2010
  - Beeson, Jack, 1999 December 1; OHV 300 a-f; Hawkshaw, Susan, (Musicologist); Approximate Running Time: 814 mins; Transcript Page Count: 352 pages
  - Beeson, Jack, 1999 December 2; OHV 300 g-m
  - Beeson, Jack, 2000 January 18; OHV 300 n-s
  - Beeson, Jack, 2000 February16; OHV 300 t-x
- Behrman, David
  - Behrman, David, 2000 March 22; OHV 304 a-b; Marshall, Ingram, 1942-; Approximate Running Time: 162 mins; Transcript Page Count: 85 pages
    Part b also ends with the beginning of next interview (OHV 304 b-d)
    Behrman, David
  - Behrman, David, 2000 May 1; OHV 304 b-d
    Part b begins with end of previous interview (OHV 304 a-b)
- Beltrami, Marco
  - Beltrami, Marco, 2023 February 8; OHV 575 a; 1 Computer File; 753 megabytes; Approximate running time: 75 mins
    Beltrami, Marco (1966-10-07-)
- Berger, Arthur
  - Berger, Arthur, 1988 September 20; OHV 198 a-b; Grimes, Ev; Approximate Running Time: 216 mins; Transcript Page Count: 61 pages
    Cambridge, MA
    Berger, Arthur, 1912-2003
  - Berger, Arthur, 1988 September 21; OHV 198 c-h
  - Berger, Arthur, 2002 November 6; OHV 198 i-l; Tick, Judith; Approximate Running Time: 115 mins
    Northeastern U, Boston, MA
- Berio, Luciano
  - Berio, Luciano, 1971 November 16; OHV 72 a; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 30 mins; Transcript Page Count: 12 pages
    Berio, Luciano, 1925-2003
- Bermel, Derek
  - Bermel, Derek, 2003 July 10; OHV 332 a-c; Marshall, Ingram, 1942-; Approximate Running Time: 141 mins; Transcript Page Count: 63 pages
    Bermel, Derek, 1967-
  - Bermel, Derek, 2003 October 23; OHV 332 d-e; Approximate Running Time: 73 mins
  - Bermel, Derek, 2019 November 21; OHV 332 f; Approximate Running Time: 74 mins
    Composition seminar presented at the Yale School of Music in New York, NY
  - Bermel, Derek, 2021 April 23; OHV 332 g; Bendian, Gregg; 1 Computer File; 1.20 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 207 mins
  - Bermel, Derek, 2021 April 30; OHV 332 h; Bendian, Gregg; 1 Computer File; 1.46 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 250 mins
- Bernstein, Elmer
  - Bernstein, Elmer, undated; OHV 319 a-f; Approximate Running Time: 428 mins
    Bernstein, Elmer (1922-04-04-)
- Bernstein, Leonard
  - Bernstein, Leonard, 1950 1955; OHV 136 g-h; Approximate Running Time: 31 mins
    Recording of Bernstein rehersing with the Boston Symphony Orchestra.
    Bernstein, Leonard, 1918-1990
  - Bernstein, Leonard, circa 1982; OHV 136 j; Page, Tim, 1954-; Approximate Running Time: 38 mins
  - Bernstein, Leonard, 1983 September 22; OHV 136 a-d; Perlis, Vivian; Approximate Running Time: 149 mins; Transcript Page Count: 50 pages
    Fairfield, CT
  - Bernstein, Leonard, undated; OHV 136 i; Approximate Running Time: 18 mins
    Leonard Bernstein discusses Charles Ives
  - Bernstein, Leonard, undated; OHV 136 k; Page, Tim, 1954-; Approximate Running Time: 59 mins
  - Foss, Lukas and Moseley, Carlos, 1988 March 1; OHV 136 e-f; Pincus, Andrew L., 1930-; Approximate Running Time: 32 mins
    Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009; Moseley, Carlos (19140921-20121001)
- Berroa, Ignacio
  - Berroa, Ignacio, 2019 September 26; OHV 533 a-c; Bendian, Gregg; Approximate Running Time: 128 mins
    The audio part of this interview is restricted. Access may be granted to a patron who has obtained direct permission from the interviewee or their estate. An edited version of the transcript is available upon request from Oral History of American Music.
    Berroa, Ignacio
- Bielawa, Lisa